cd-adapco.com 2015-12-09

# PRIVACY POLICY | CD-adapco

**PRIVACY POLICY**

CD-adapco respects the privacy of all individuals entrusting us with their personal information and is committed to maintaining this information securely. This commitment is reflected in the principles and standards on handling personal data outlined in this Privacy Policy.

This Policy applies to Computational Dynamics Limited (CD), Analysis & Design Application Co., Ltd. (adapco) and its affiliated companies, collectively referred to as “CD-adapco”, and constitutes a global policy governing the manner in which CD-adapco handles all personally identifiable data collected in the normal course of day-to-day business operations.

This Privacy Policy is valid for:

  * All  individuals  providing  CD-adapco  with  their  personal  information  for  business  related purposes, including but not limited to customers, business partners, vendors, and visitors to CD- adapco’s website;
  * All locations where CD-adapco operates, even where local regulations do not exist;
  * All  methods  of  data  collection,  including  in  person,  written,  via  the  Internet,  direct  mail, telephone, or facsimile; and
  * All personal data being collected and processed in the United States as well as personal data collected outside of the United States and transferred for processing to CD-adapco facilities in the United States;

**SCOPE**

This is a Global Policy and its principles shall apply  to all personal data originating outside of the United  
States and being transferred for processing to CD-adapco facilities in the United States.

CD-adapco facilities outside of the United States are required to comply with this Policy in addition to the privacy laws in force under their local jurisdictions. This Policy does not necessarily describe how local management may handle personal data in order to comply with local privacy laws.  Local management will be responsible for accessing and complying with local/unique laws and/or rules regarding the processing of personal information in that particular locale.

**ADHERENCE TO EU LAWS**

CD-adapco’s Privacy Policy has been designed to comply with the _EU Model Clauses for Data Transfer and Processing_ \- standard contractual clauses for the transfer of personal data to, and processing by, controllers outside EU/EEA established under Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council.

CD-adapco shall maintain its compliance with these clauses by observing the key privacy principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement, which restrict the use and disclosure of EU-origin - personal information maintained in the U.S.

For purposes of this policy, “personal data” is information:

  * about a specific person including persons affiliated with an entity being an existing or potential customer, vendor or business partner of CD-adapco or one of its subsidiaries or affiliates,
  * that can be linked to that particular person and
  * that is being maintained and processed in the U.S.

**NOTICE**

CD-adapco may collect personal information in various ways and on various occasions. This may include, but is not limited to, the situations where individuals initiate contact with us, visit our website, participate in a promotional activity or register for any services and events offered by CD-adapco.

**_What information is maintained_**

The information collected by CD-adapco may include, but is not limited to:

  * _Personally identifiable information_ such as: name, address, email address, telephone and facsimile number, company affiliation, department name, title;
  * _Administrative information_ such as: quote history, licensing history, login information to customer portal and other CD-adapco online resources;
  * _Marketing information_ such as: type of industry, meeting and event attendance, support case issues;
  * _Billing information_ such as: billing address, credit card information;

VAT identification number; For the purpose of supplying software licenses under CD-adapco’s Global Academic Program, in addition  
to the basic contact and administrative information, the following types of personal data are collected about the students requesting CD-adapco products:

> o  graduation date  
>  o  name of the attended academic institution   
>  o  type of degree   
>  o  area of study   
>  o  research/ application interests   
>  o  publications

**_How information is used_**

CD-adapco collects and uses personal information in the conduct of its regular business operations and activities. In particular, such collected _Personal Information_ may be used for any of the following purposes:

  * to contact customers in response to their queries and communication requests;
  * to provide requested software licenses, engineering consulting services and technical support;
  * to  provide  requested  product  updates  and  upgrades,  special  offers,  pricing  information, newsletters, and other information;
  * to  undertake  any  other  promotional  activities  where  the  customer  has  consented  to  such promotional activities;
  * in connection with license keys, access codes or other information as may be required to permit access to CD-adapco’s websites or servers to receive products, updates or services;
  * to help verify that existing personal information in our possession is accurate and complete;
  * to  determine  the  country  of  customer  location  for  compliance  purposes  (including  without limitation export compliance) and for security, anti-piracy, and fraud prevention purposes;
  * to verify compliance with applicable laws, rules and regulations;

_Anonymous Information_ collected by CD-adapco may be used among others:

  * to personalize customer experience with this website and related web resources;
  * to improve the functionality of CD-adapco’s website, products and services;
  * to deliver targeted advertisements on this website; and
  * for other historical, statistical or research and analysis purposes.

**CHOICE OF DATA USE**

CD-adapco respects each individual’s rights to make decisions about the manner in which CD-adapco uses, collects or discloses personal information about them to third parties.

CD-adapco does not intend to use or share with third parties any personal information obtained from its customers, vendors, business partners or other parties for purposes other than for which it was originally collected without the prior consent of the concerned individuals. All individuals providing CD-adapco with their personal data may direct CD-adapco not to share such personal information with any third party or request that CD-adapco not utilize such data for any secondary purposes. CD-adapco will respect these choices.

For example, the customers may “opt out” from the marketing email distribution or participation in a support survey. Such “opt-out” requests may be submitted at  any time to  the appropriate Account Manager at CD-adapco or to [info@cd-adapco.com](mailto:info@cd-adapco.com)

With respect to sensitive personal information (such as information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, and religious or philosophical beliefs) CD-adapco does not intend to collect such data in the conduct of its business operations.. If such sensitive personal data is provided to CD-adapco, CD-adapco obligates itself not to share it with third parties or use it for purposes other than originally intended without an explicit direction and consent of the concerned individual.

Visitors to CD-adapco’s website have an option of deleting or rejecting cookies and other automated data collection tools in use by CD-adapco by adjusting the cookies settings in their browser.

**TRANSFER TO THIRD PARTIES**

Personal information may sometimes be disclosed to third parties in furtherance of the primary sales and customer support related activities or fulfillment of other contractual obligations, or as otherwise required

by law. These recipients may include third parties acting as an agent to perform tasks on behalf of and under the instructions of CD-adapco, such as, for example credit card processors, sub-contractors, legal advisors, or consultants. Personal information may also be disclosed, as appropriate, to taxation authorities, law enforcement authorities, other regulatory bodies, or potential purchasers or customers of CD-adapco.

Prior to disclosure of any personal data to a third party, CD-adapco will confirm that the third party agrees to maintain confidentiality and security of personal data entrusted to them by CD-adapco and has adequate procedures in place to do so.

**SECURITY**

CD-adapco is committed to keeping personal information secure and has therefore implemented reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards designed to protect personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. These safeguards, among others, may include:

1)   Physical measures:

  * Locked filing cabinets
  * Restricting access to offices
  * Alarm systems

2)   Technological tools:

  * Password protection for electronic information systems
  * Firewalls
  * Encryption of stored and in-transit data

3)   Administrative controls:

  * Security clearances
  * Limiting access to a need-to-know basis
  * Same day processing and shredding of customer credit card information
  * Staff training
  * Confidentiality agreements
  * Secure deletion or disposal of obsolete personal information stored in both electronic and hardcopy form

CD-adapco uses industry standard methods for collection and transmittal of sensitive information such as a  financial account number. It is important for customers to understand, however, that no website, database or system is completely secure. CD-adapco expects all concerned individuals to share the responsibility of taking reasonable steps to protect their personal information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse, for example, by protecting their password./p>

**AUTOMATIC DATA COLLECTION TOOLS (COOKIES)**   
CD-adapco uses automated data collection tools including cookies to monitor activities on its website. Cookies are tiny elements of data that are placed on a computer’s hard drive by a web browser when a  
website is accessed. Cookies are used for the purpose of authenticating clients, providing time-saving   
shortcuts and preferences or sending targeted advertisements to potential customers based on their browsing habits.

The cookies used by CD-adapco include session cookies which are deleted once the browser of the individual using our company website is closed and persistent cookies which remain on the user’s computer for a longer period of time. The cookies are set in order to track activities on CD-adapco website for our internal marketing and statistics purposes as well as to create the best browsing experience for the users returning to our site by remembering their preferences such as form field values.

The data contained in the cookies that CD-adapco uses is completely anonymous and does not contain personally identifiable information. CD-adapco may combine this information with information obtained from other sources to improve its completeness. **Users may opt-out from this automatic data collection by setting the appropriate cookie preferences in their web browser.** Users may view and delete cookies selectively or block them completely. In a few cases blocking cookies may reduce the functionality of our sites. The cookie settings can be adjusted at any time by referring to the help menu on the internet browser. The continued use of the CD-adapco website without opting out of this automatic data collection signifies your consent to CD-adapco’s use of cookies.

**DATA ACCESS AND INTEGRITY**

CD-adapco strives to maintain the accuracy and integrity of the personal information in its databases and to keep that information up-to-date.  To the extent permitted or required by applicable law, CD-adapco provides ways for its customers to access and verify the individually identifiable information maintained about them by CD-adapco in order to update them or correct inaccuracies. Customers who have been granted access to the customer support portal can self-verify and update online the following types of information: name, phone number, email, industry, time zone, locale and language. As the information loses value over time or becomes obsolete it will be periodically deleted, in accordance with applicable local legal records retention requirements.

All individuals seeking to update or correct their personal information or to change their communication preference with CD-adapco should contact the appropriate Account Manager or email their request to [info@cd-adapco.com](mailto:info@cd-adapco.com)

**ENFORCEMENT**

CD-adapco utilizes the self-assessment approach to ensure its compliance with this Privacy Policy. CD- adapco periodically verifies that this Privacy Policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information needed to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented, and in conformity with the EU Model Clauses for Data Transfer and Processing. Annual internal compliance reviews of this Policy takes place as a part of the Company’s due diligence in privacy protection.

CD-adapco investigates and  resolves  any  complaints and  disputes  regarding  use  and  disclosure  of personal information in accordance with the principles contained in this Policy. Claims arising out of or relating to CD-adapco’s processing of EU-origin personal data that cannot be resolved through CD- adapco’s internal processes, will be settled through the arbitration, mediation or other dispute proceeding developed for data protection disputes.

Any complaints regarding improper use or disclosure of personal data or any questions related to this Privacy Policy should be directed to Leslie Browne, Manager Worldwide Human Resources of CD- adapco as follows:

_By mail:  _ | CD-adapco  
Analysis & Design Application Co., Ltd.  
60 Broadhollow Rd  
Melville, NY 11747  
USA _           _  
Attention: Leslie Browne, Manager Worldwide Human Resources  
---|---  
  
_Or by email_ :     [legal@cd-adapco.com](mailto:arlene.soucy@cd-adapco.com)

**CHANGES TO POLICY**

This policy may be amended from time to time in a manner consistent with the requirements of the EU Model Clauses for Data Transfer and Processing and CD-adapco’s business needs. Such revisions will apply to information maintained at the time of the change. Appropriate notice will be provided concerning revisions and amendments.
